Guide to the John P. Robin Papers, 1943-2000 AIS.1977.06
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Port Authority of Allegheny County, 1970-1993; VI.
  - Newspaper articles, Professional correspondence, Operating budget (1977); Bound report regarding – Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Quarterly progress report, Federal transit subsidies; Loose documents pertaining to - Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles, Mass Transit Magazine, Port Authority People Flyer, Port Authority News releases, 1974-1977 (Box 9)
  - Professional correspondence, Port Authority resolutions, Agenda of the Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Testimony of Executive Director James R. Maloney, Transit advertising and the Port Authority, Financial statements; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Quarterly progress reports, Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Population estimates (1976), Bridge closing impact study; Presentation folders on – Light Rail, here Rivers Regatta, Toronto Transit Commission; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Port Authority News releases, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Regular meeting f the board agenda, Transit in Toronto, Public Transportation, Transit Journal, Light Rail Today, The Future of Rail transit, 1975-1980 (Box 22)
  - Audit and Financial Committee professional correspondence, Audit and Financial Committee meeting minutes, Consumer Relations/Operation Committee professional correspondence, Pennsylvania Transit Financial Conference (1985), Budget professional correspondence, Port of Pittsburgh; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Operating budget (1986), Disadvantaged Business Enterprise Program, Chronology (1985), Mon Valley Transit study, Comprehensive Marketing Plan, Survey of State Involvement in Public Transportation (1984); Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Senate Bill No. 825, Newspaper articles, 1982-1987 (Box 24)
  - Consumer Relations Committee meeting minutes, consumer letters, Construction Committee meeting minutes, Audit and Finance Committee meeting minutes, Administration Committee meeting minutes; (1982) Port Authority Regular Meeting of the board - Meeting minutes, Meeting agenda, Professional correspondence; (1988) Port Authority Regular meeting of the board – Meeting minutes, Meeting agenda, Professional correspondence, Staff report to the board; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Proposed access fares, Recommendations, to improve the fare structure; Loose documents pertaining to – Meeting agenda, meeting minutes, Professional correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box 28)
  - Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Strategic Plan (1987-1991), Pa Monthly financial report, Port Authority Strategic Business Plan (1986-1990), Port Authority Operating Budget (1986), Transit Fact Book; Loose documents pertaining to – Mayor's Development Council meeting minutes, Professional correspondence, Pa Inter office correspondence, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Rider comments and suggestions, 1981-1991 (Box 31)
  - Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, 1977 (Box 32-B)
  - Port Authority Regular meeting of the board – agenda, professional correspondence, inter office correspondence; Newspaper articles, Employment Impacts, of Transit Capital Investment and Operating Expenditures, Monthly financial report, Port Authority Inter office correspondence, Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Quarterly progress reports, Mass Transit Magazine, Bus Ride Magazine, Public Hearing on Proposed Fare Increase and Service Reductions, Port Authority Staff report to the board; Presentation folder – Professional correspondence, Metro Magazine; Loose documents pertaining to –PA Transit news releases, Professional correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box 43)
  - Port Authority Regular meeting of the board and Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Professional correspondence, Port Authority Inter office correspondence, Port Authority Fact Finder; Port Authority Inter office correspondence; Baumbash – Port Authority Inter office correspondence, Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Quarterly progress reports, Staff responses to opinion and order, Port Authority Transit Funding Study; Loose documents pertaining to – PA Transit news releases, Professional correspondence, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Inter office correspondence, Newspaper articles, Port Authority People Flyer, 1979-1982 (Box 44)
  - Court case documents, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles, Port Authority Code of Performance, Professional correspondence, inter office correspondence, Request for Proposal: Streetcar System Derailment Evaluation, Port Authority Monthly financial report, Transit Advertising and the Port Authority; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, A Revised Transportation Plan of Southwestern Pennsylvania, Port Authority Quarterly progress reports, The Highway Fact Book, Port Authority Hearing on Proposed Fare Increase and/or Service Reductions, Graphics Standard Manual; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority Special meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Professional correspondence, Photocopy of a letter to James Maloney from President Carter, A Survey of Local Mechanisms for Finding Transit Operating Costs, Request for Proposal for the Operation of a County Wide Shelter Program, PA Transit news releases, 1977-1981 (Box 45)
  - John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board, minutes, and agendas, Professional and Inter office correspondence, Port Authority Staff reports to the board, Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Newspaper articles, "When the Courts Decide the Fares," A Report of the Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh; Renaissance II, Report on Transit Operations, Information on Street Cars, Affirmative Action Plan for the Minority Business Enterprise,; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Monthly financial report, Operating budget (1979), Port of Pittsburgh Profile, PA Transit news releases, Audit report of Port Authority, 1973-1982 (Box 46)
  - John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board, and agendas, Port Authority Staff reports to the board, Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Quarterly progress reports, Professional and Inter office correspondence, The Academy for Contemporary Problems memorandum, PA Transit news releases, Tri-State Rivers Seminar, Testimony of the Port Authority of Allegheny County, Symposium on Transportation Issues, Pittsburgh Light Rail Transit Reconstruction, Highway Planning and Research Work Program; Presentation folder on – Federal Funding of Transit; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes and agendas, Port Authority People Flyer, PA Transit news releases, 1975-1979 (Box 57)
  - John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board and agendas, Professional correspondence, Customer Letters, Newspaper articles, PA Transit news releases, Transit Fare Summaries; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Quarterly progress report, Monthly financial reports; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, and minutes, Port Authority People Flyer, Newspaper articles, PA Transit news release, 1980-1981 (Box 59)
  - John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority report for fiscal year (1979-1980), South Hills Light Rail Transit, Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Spine Line Feasibility Study, Comparative Analysis Study of Alternative Transit Systems: South Hills Corridor, Executive session of the board; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Newspaper articles, 1973-1985 (Box 60)
  - Audit (1984) – Port Authority board members, by-laws, history, financial status, and technical studies; Port Authority Equal Opportunity Program; Bound reports regarding – Second Class County Port Authority Act, Urban Transport: Sector Policy paper, Public Hearing on Proposed Service Reduction, Port Authority Proposal for new fare structure, Port Authority Strategic Plan (1987-1991), Port Authority discussion of strategic issues; Presentation folder for – Rapid Transit Conference (1989); Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles, Proposed Garage Rehabilitation Program, 1971-1992 (Box 65)
  - Bound reports regarding – Spine Line Feasibility study, Metropolitan Transportation, Riverfront Renaissance: A Comprehensive Strategy for the Pittsburgh Riverfront, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Operating & Capital Improvement budget (1990); Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda and minutes, John P. Robin Port Authority resignation letter, 1980-1993 (Box 66)
  - Allegheny County Transit Council – News releases, meeting agenda, and professional correspondence; Consumer Relations/Operations Committee meeting minutes, Planning and Construction meeting minutes, Administration and Finance Committee meeting minutes, documents relating to Port Authority Union and Airport Busway; Bound reports regarding – Parkway West Multi-Modal Corridor study, Port Authority Operating and Capital Improvement budgets, Phase 1 Airport Busway/Wabash HOV/Alternatives Analysis/Draft Environment Impact statement, 1984-1993 (Box 69)
  - Administration and Finance Committee meeting minutes, Consumer Relations/Operating Committee meeting minutes, Planning and Construction Committee meeting minutes, Port Authority Operating and Capital Improvement budgets (1989-1990),; John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board and agendas, Professional correspondence, Customer letters, Newspaper articles; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda and minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 70)
  - John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board, agendas, and minutes, Port Authority of Allegheny Count Resolution, Port Authority Program for mass Transportation Services for Handicapped persons, Port Authority capital budget (1988), Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles, Trolley Wire-Pittsburgh Light Rail Project report, Report to the APTA Transit board members seminar, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Annual Report (1987-1987), Allegheny County Transit Council meeting minutes and agenda, 1982-1990 (Box 79)
  - Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the Board; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority Regular meeting of the agenda and minutes, Port Authority Special meeting of the board minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 81)
  - Planning Committee of the Board of the Port Authority agenda, Testimony of the Port Authority before the House Sub-Committee on Mass Transportation; John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board and agendas, Strategic planning for transit, Absenteeism Reduction Demonstration Project, Administrative Committee of the Port Authority meeting minutes, Prototype study on management and operations for Port Authority, Professional correspondence, newspaper articles; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Minority Business Enterprise Program, Salary Administration Program; Loose documents pertaining to – Pt Regular meeting of the board agenda and minutes, Port Authority Special meeting of the board agenda, Professional correspondence, 1974-1984 (Box 83)
  - John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board, agendas, and minutes, Professional and Inter office correspondence, Fiscal strategies for Pennsylvania, Mt. Lebanon: The Community Magazine, PA Transit News articles, Newspaper articles; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Quarterly progress reports; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority People Flyer, PA Transit news articles, Professional and Inter office correspondence, Allegheny County Planning Commission meeting minutes, Administrative Committee meeting minutes, Allegheny County Transit Council meeting minutes, Consumer Relations Committee minutes, 1978-1985 (Box 86)
- Professional Publications, 1961-1972; VII.
  This series contains several professional publications such as Audubon magazine, City magazine, D.A. Review magazine, Ekistics magazine, Human settlements magazine, Journal of Mammalogy, The Sun magazine, and Dialogue magazine.
  - Various bound publications including – Athens Technological Organization/Athens Center of Ekistics, Audubon magazine, Town Planning Institute Singapore Branch magazine, City magazine, D.A. Review magazine, Congo-Afrique, Ekistics magazine; Loose publications pertaining to – The American Country magazine, Architecture, Town Planning, Surveying, Engineering magazine, African Wildlife Leadership Foundation, 1968-1972 (Box 18)
  - Exapolis 2000 & Population Societies; Various bound publications including – Ekistics magazine, Human Settlements magazine, Journal of Mammology, Finance and Development magazine, Challenge Breakthrough magazine, 1970-1972 (Box 19)
  - Various bound publications including – The Sun magazine, Public Administration Newsletter, Philippine Planning Journal, Dialogue magazine, NIPA Journal, Volunteer magazine, Monthly Commentary magazine, The Sunday Times magazine, 1961-1972 (Box 20)
- University of Pittsburgh, 1985-1994; VIII.
  This series contains documents pertaining to the Advisory Council of Regional Development (ACORD), the Institute of Politics, and the PITT Benchmark Index Advisory Committee. There are ACROD documents such as meeting minutes and agendas, expense reports, budgets, newspaper articles, and professional correspondence documents. In addition, there are Institute of Politics documents such as meeting minutes and agendas. The Benchmark documents include items such as meeting agendas, newspaper articles, reports, and professional correspondence documents.
  - Advisory Council on Regional Development (ACORD) – Professional Correspondence, expense report, and budget; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional Correspondence, Institute of Politics – memorandum, Joint meeting of the board agenda and minutes, 1988-1993 (Box 63-A)
  - Various documents concerning – ACORD and Benchmarks II; Bounds reports regarding – ACORD and Pittsburgh Benchmarks; Loos documents pertaining to – Profession Correspondence, The University's Economic Development Initiatives, 1985-1994 (Box 78)
- Urban Redevelopment Authority, 1943-1994; IX.
  This series contains Urban Redevelopment Authority meeting minutes and agendas, financial statements, quarterly reports, professional correspondence documents, Executive Committee meeting minutes, Citizens Sponsoring Committee meeting minutes, Mayor Caliguiri speeches, Pittsburgh Cultural Trust District Development Committee meeting minutes and agendas, and Mayor's Task Force on Entertainment Center Development meeting minutes and agendas. In addition, there are documents pertaining to specific projects such as the Convention Center proposal and redevelopment area plan, Lower Hill proposal, Hazelwood proposal, North Side neighborhood revitalization program, North Shore project, Market Square proposal redevelopment area plan, Smallman Street reconstruction project, Herr's Island, YMCA initiative, Buhl Science Center, Parkway East industrial park, Pittsburgh Technology Center, Washington's Landing, Forks of the Ohio National Park, and Schenely Park.
  - Bound reports regarding - 601 Liberty, Public Sector Prospectus, Financial Study No. 5 for Public Parking Authority of Pittsburgh, Convention Center Proposal and Redevelopment Area Plan, Lower Hill Proposal and Modification No. 5 to the Plan, Hazelwood Proposal and Modification No. 1 to the Redevelopment Area Plan, Land Use and Housing Plan, City of Charleston, SC, Recommended Priority Highway System Plan, Housing Subsidy Programs, Greenway Revised Proposal and Modification No. 1 to the Redevelopment Area Plan, North Side Neighborhood Revitalization Program Progress Report, Final Technical Report, Penn/Liberty Urban Design Study, North Shore Project Report; Presentation folder; Loose documents pertaining to – Forest City Enterprises Annual Report, Charleston Waterfront Park Master Plan, Pittsburgh Perceived: A Design Image of Pittsburgh, 1963-1983 (Box 23)
  - Bound reports regarding - URA Report on Examination of Financial Statements and Additional Information, URA Home Improvement Loan Program, URA Mortgage Revenue Bond Program, Analysis of Major Commercial Districts, Court Deposition, Monongahela Wharf Promenade and Parking Deck Study, Market Square Proposal Redevelopment Area Plan, Golden Triangle Association Annual Report, Downtown at CMU, ACTION-Housing, Inc. Twenty-five years of housing and neighborhood improvements, Renaissance II The Inside Story; Presentation folder containing – When Housing Rehabilitation Confronts the 80's, UDAG Luncheon Program, ATION Housing, RIDC Industrial Park; Loose documents pertaining to - Professional Correspondence, Allegheny County Marina Study, North Shore Urban Design Consulting Services, Lower Hill Redevelopment Area Plan, An Analysis of Solid Waste Disposal in Pittsburgh, Smallman Street Reconstruction Project, Homewood Commercial Revitalization Program, 1976-1985 (Box 25)
  - Bound reports regarding – Silver Lake, Report on Examination and Financial Statements, JR Associates Submission for Development of East Liberty Great High School site; Presentation folder containing – Pittsburgh Partnership for Neighborhood Development; Loose documents pertaining to – URA meeting minutes and agenda, professional correspondence, 1977-1984 (Box 26)
  - Bound reports regarding – North Shore Proposal for Redevelopment Activities, Homewood South Proposal and Modification No. 3 to the Redevelopment Area Plan; Loose documents pertaining o – URA meeting minutes and agenda, professional correspondence, 1977-1987 (Box 27)
  - Various committee meeting minutes, Bound reports regarding- Mayor's Development Workshop, Briefing Materials, Mini-Grants for Teachers, Partnerships in Education, Mount Washington: Duquesne Heights, A Program for Implementation, Mount Washington: Duquesne Heights, A Study for the Department of Parks and Rec, Solid Waste Resource Recovery: Full Scale Test Report, The Firstside Cultural District Plan: "A Strategy for Revitalization", Fox Chapel: A Comprehensive Development Plan, Community Development for Homewood-Brushton, Allegheny Conference Education Fund, Urban Redevelopment Authority: Department of Housing: Housing Subsidy Programs; Presentation folder contacting – A Landmark Proposal for Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh Hydroelectric Project Design Highlights, DiSuvero Sculpture Island Project; Loos documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Mayor's Development Council meeting minutes, Basic Expressway System: Program Status Update, 1977-1988 (Box 30)
  - Bound reports regarding – URA Quarterly report, Downtown Development in Renaissance II: Cost Benefit Study; Presentation folder containing – Garfield Jubilee Association; loose document pertaining to – URA meeting minutes and agenda, Quarterly reports, 1979-1988 (Box 32-A)
  - United Manchester Redevelopment Authority report, URA Agenda, Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding – Herr's Island Pittsburgh Proposal for Redevelopment Activity, URA Report on Examination and Financial Statements; Loose documents pertaining to – URA agenda and memorandum, Newspaper articles, City of Pittsburgh Neighborhood Revitalization Mortgage Loan Program, Modification No. 5 to the Lower Hill Area Plan, 1970-1984 (Box 34)
  - URA Bloomfield/Garfield, URA Financial Department: CEO Venture Fund, URA YMCA Building, Buhl Science Center, Market Square; Presentation folder containing – Manchester Citizens Corporation; Bound reports regarding - Women Business Enterprise in Pittsburgh: Research, Policy Analysis, Program Development, Economic Development Department: 1986 Report, A generation of Economic Change in the City of Pittsburgh, Neighborhood Food Stores in Pittsburgh, Economic Development Department: 1991 Annual Report, Performance Audit of Economic Development Department, Pittsburgh's Neighborhood Business District: Revitalization Program, Urban Redevelopment Authority Quarterly Reports, Financial Assistance Programs, Urban Redevelopment Authority Financial Statements; Loose documents pertaining to – URA memorandum, professional correspondence, Manchester proposal, 1977-1994 (Box 62)
  - Allegheny County Planning agenda and minutes, Bridges, Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding - Institute of Politics Reports, Issues, The University of Pittsburgh Issues Publications, Taking Flight: Pittsburgh International Airport, Airport Area Economic Development, Annual Report on Southwestern Pennsylvania's Bridge Conditions, Southwestern PA Regional Planning Commission (SPRPC) Reports, Pittsburgh Magazine, Remaking the Monongahela Valley; Loose documents pertaining to – Airport Area Development Commission, Professional correspondence Newspaper articles, Southwester PA Regional Planning Commission reports, 1976-1993 (Box 63-B)